Abdelaziz El Idrissi

Front-end Web Developer React / Next js

Email me: elidrissiabdalaziz@gmail.com

Call me: 0647745783

Portfolio

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/el-idrissi-abdelaziz/

Address: Rabat

PROFIL

My name is Abdelaziz El Idrissi, and I have 1 year of experience in the tech industry, Experienced in React. I prioritize responsive design, Ux/Ui, SEO, and committing to best practices.

Beyond my technical skills, I'm a sporty and sociable person, bringing positive energy to the workplace.

I'm open to new opportunities where I can join your development team as a Front-end Web Developer, learn more, meet new people in the field, and add value to your company.

PROJECTS

E-commerce application using React Js, Next Js



Personal Project - Rabat, MAR

- I created an e-commerce application with features including adding, modifying, and deleting products, a single product page, checkout, and purchase success page using Tailwindcss, Flexbox, Grid, and reusable components with state management.
- I managed all aspects of the web development project, from design to deployment using best practices.

SKILLS: HTML, CSS, TailwindCss, Javascript, Typescript, React JS, Next js, app router, Context api, Resend, Analytics, NodeJS, github actions CI/CD, vercel deployment, Eslint, local storage

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

ALX AiCE - AI Career Essentials Student

ALX_AFRICA

March 2024 - April 2023 (2 months Internship)

- Improved proficiency in utilizing workplace tools effectively and professionally.
- · Demonstrated expertise in work planning and time management, problem-solving, proactive communication, and collaboration with colleagues in meetings.
- Boosted productivity by using specialized AI tools for specific tasks including programming and design

SKILLS: Loom, Chat-Gpt, BlackBox, UiZard, Runway, Grammarly, Julius

Front End Web Developer

SOLI DIGITAL EXPERIENCE - Rabat

March 2023 - August 2023 (6 months Internship)

- · Developed user interfaces using React and implemented state management and responsive design.
- Collaborated with a team of 24 developers and implemented Git version control.
- Understood the roles of E-commerce forms, including B2B and B2C.
- · Actively contributed to team meetings to discuss best development practices
- Develop my communication skills and speed of learning.
- · Collaborated with test teams to ensure software quality and make patches for identified issues.

SKILLS: Html, Css, Tailwind, Javascript, React.js, Figma, Git, RESTFul APIs, Bitbucket, Postman, Jenkins, Docker

Graphic Designer

KacimiGraphic, printing house - Rabat

February 2023 - March 2023 (Work)

- Execution of the design process to printing, preparing files and works of art for production, demonstrating attention to detail and compliance with printing standards.
- Contribution to the design and production of custom trophies, leveraging the creative skills of Adobe Illustrator
- Collaboration with the design team to bring creative ideas and concepts, ensuring collaborative visual communication on various materials.

SKILLS: Adobe illustrator, Canva, Design-to-print process, Collaboration, Creativity

C# Desktop Developer

Management app for a beauty salon - Kenitra

April 2021 - May 2021

• I developed a desktop application in C# WinForms for the management of a salon, sold at the price of 3000 Dh. This application simplified day-to-day operations, increasing the number of regular customers and helping increase the profitability of the business.

SKILLS: C#, Windows forms, SQLite, Visual studio

EXTRA-PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Successfully led and managed a team of 8 people during a week-long volunteer initiative dedicated to strengthening security measures for the international event «The World Sufi Gathering in Morocco» for Aid al Mawlid in Berkane 2023.
- Proactive supervisor ensuring the well-being of 20 children during a trip to Ifrane for an organization. Focused on organization and safety to create a positive experience.

CERTIFICATIONS

Generative AI Explained

- NVIDIA
- Febraury 2024 March 2023

Postman API Fundamentals Student Expert CERTIFICATION

- · Canvas Credentials (Badgr)
- August 2023 September 2023

English and Microsoft office certification

- · Centre de formation ASMADEC
- January 2020 March 2020

EDUCATION

Diploma of technician specialized in computer development

Specialized Institute of Applied Management Technology Yaacoub El Mansour RABAT | OFPPT 2020 - 2022

Baccalaureat in Mechanical Science and Technology

Les orangers RABAT 2017 - 2018

LANGUAGES

· Native language: Arabic | Fluent English | Intermediate French